<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>siddharth&#39;s home </title>
    <link>https://tanwarsid.github.io/tags/eng/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on siddharth&#39;s home </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Siddharth Tanwar</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/eng/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Good and Evil</title>
      <link>https://tanwarsid.github.io/project/eng/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanwarsid.github.io/project/eng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Course Project under course ENG458 - Literature and the Individual&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conflict between good and evil has been thematized by writers since earliest times understood
ofcourse in a religious context. There are several variations on this conflict, one being the battle
between individuals or ideologies, with one side good, the other evil. Another variation is the inner
struggle in characters (and by extension, humans in reality) between good and evil. What we regard
as good is a peaceful order with the idea of a “rule of law”. Culture strives to establish a boundary
between itself and savagery. The manifestations of savegery are called &amp;ldquo;crimes&amp;rdquo; which we consider
evil. And thus there exists this conflict between two competing impulses within all human beings:
the instinct to live by rules, act peacefully, follow moral commands, and value the good of the group
against the instinct to gratify one’s immediate desires, act violently to obtain supremacy over others,
and enforce one’s will. Through my study of the 1954 Novel by Nobel prize winning English author
William Goulding&amp;rsquo;s Lord of the Flies I intend to explore the qualities of human nature and the
conflicting state within each character. The book grapples with the underlying theme or order vs
chaos and loss of innocence when a small group of schoolboys find themselves stranded on an
island after a planecrash. Through their story of existence in a community without boundaries, we
can get a better understanding of the need of a social, political and moral construct within us and
our society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the detailed report &lt;a href=&#34;lord_of_the_flies.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and presentation &lt;a href=&#34;Lord of the Flies.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
