<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>siddharth&#39;s home </title>
    <link>https://tanwarsid.github.io/tags/quadrotors/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on siddharth&#39;s home </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Siddharth Tanwar</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/quadrotors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Marker based Localization of a Quadrotor</title>
      <link>https://tanwarsid.github.io/project/quadloc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanwarsid.github.io/project/quadloc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Course Project under course EE698G - Probabilistic Mobile Robotics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Followed ICRA’15 paper ”Precise quadrotor autonomous landing with SRUKF vision perception”
by S. Yang et al. to implement a high level control pipeline on a quadrotor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used Aruco Markers and library in ROS framework to estimate pose from images and experimented
by fusing this with onboard IMU and Sonar sensor data using Extended Kalman Filter
(EKF), Unscented Kalman Filter (UKF) and Square-Root Unscented Kalman Filter (SRUKF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our team of two won the &lt;strong&gt;Best Presentation Award&lt;/strong&gt; for the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the detailed report &lt;a href=&#34;ee698g_project_report.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and presentation &lt;a href=&#34;EE698G_Presentation.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensory fusion, Pose Estimation and Controller Design on Quadrotors</title>
      <link>https://tanwarsid.github.io/project/quad/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tanwarsid.github.io/project/quad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project aimed at autonomous indoor and outdoor navigation of an Asctec Pelican quadrotor
equipped with GPS, IMU and visual and ultrasonic sensors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented SLAM based algorithm SVO (Semi-direct Monocular Visual Odometry) using ROS framework and OpenCV on Asctec Pelican quadrotor to estimate pose in an outdoor environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fused data obtained from GPS, monocular bottom facing camera and IMU using Extended Kalman Filter to refine results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simulated a cascade PID position controller of the Quadrotor on Matlab-Simulink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
